Hi, in this lesson, I want to share with you some really practical use cases that you
will understand better what you can do with your hubcob pilot as a React developer.
So, and as the first topic, you can understand the React code to be scoped pilot.
For example, if you have a codebase where you, which you see is the first time or some big
feature where you just join, and you want to understand better how the scoped works,
you can always ask a pilot.
For example, you can ask how work and authentication flow.
You can just select the files with the context and ask how it works.
You can ask, okay, what's the difference between data flow in this components or you
can ask to add some documentation to some hooks or functions and it try to explain it
to you.
The next use case is when you refactoring some React components.
So, it can help you improve your code, split some components through name, props, or even
simplify logic.
For example, you can ask police refactor, me this large component into smaller ones.
It will do the refactoring and do the suggestions to you.
It can also rename some confusing props in, for example, in some forms of components pages.
It can simplify logic, for example, when you use a lot of hooks, a lot of functions you
can select everything and just ask, okay, what do you think it can be simplified or optimised.
The next use case, you can convert your React code to another language framework.
It's especially useful when you do the project migration from older frameworks to newer
frameworks.
You can also ask a file by file to do the migration.
So, when it also helps to you, we will assist it with that migration.
So, like you can convert React components to view components, so for example, rewrite
some hooks, or for example, you can, if you have React class components and you don't
want to die it, how it works, you can ask, okay, please convert this code to React hooks.
Okay, the next use case is the building React features.
For example, we need to build user authentication or some simple login form with registration
pages.
You can ask a pilot, this build me a login page with this type of fields, this user's
library fault, and notification, etc, and it does some draft for you.
So, it doesn't mean that it will be in perfect code, you of course need to touch it and
do some refactoring, but it will provide you ideas and a draft, so which you can start
and save your time.
You can ask, also, create from your responsive navigation with React folders, sidebar, so
it will do some layout work for you.
You can also ask to do some data management, for example, if you need to build to do list
and state, and store this date in somewhere in state management, or a local storage, a
compiler also can do it for you.
For example, you can provide a context of the main files where you want to write a test,
you can write instructions, how you usually do it or provide it.
Other test files, the context, and you can write a case, please write me a unit test, please
write me some component test, integration test, some snapshot test, so it can do whatever
you ask.
So, you can also modelize in a legacy React code.
As I told you on one previous slide, if you for example use some last React components,
it was written by a team I know two, three, five years ago, you can ask React to convert
it.
But you always need to be careful and be responsible for what you get from a file, because
of course, you might need to change it to fix some, so it's not always ideal, but it's
a good start to start with something.
You can also like add me some prop types or add some type scripts, so we also can do it
for you, so you can save your time.
The next use case, it's update React dependencies, for example, you use React 18 and you want
to upgrade it to the new React version to 19, you can also ask a pilot to do it.
For example, you use some low dash libraries and you need to fix critical dependencies,
so you can also ask how to, or it will update it for you or it will provide you an instruction
how you can do an update and what, for example, you need to check.
For example, in another use case, you want to migrate from one state management to another
one, so we can also can do it, or you can pick some break-in changes when you're migrating
from one to another tool.
What I like is, a pilot really can help you debug your files.
For example, when Samsung doesn't work, or you can ask questions, okay, please add some
tons of logs to my code to help me to debug the bug or in your IDE, for example, generate
me ideas why it doesn't work, why is this component rendering or why is this form doesn't
emit data, so we can generate you ideas, how we can test, how we can debug it, it might
add some console log or debug points to your code, so you can more easily debug it.
Of course, you can learn, react, and write in documentation better and easier with your pilot.
For example, what I mean learning react, you can ask some questions, some theory, some
functions, how it works, please explain me really simple as a 6-yard child, or my grandma,
yeah, so it will provide you an easy explanation, so we can also ask what difference between
methods libraries, what you recommend to use.
About writing documentation, if you have a lot of components, for example, you have your
API and you want to document it, you can always ask, okay, please provide the documentation,
or use just doc to add some documentation as a comment in my code, so you can review it,
of course, fix, update it a bit, but it's save your time and it can really generate
also read me for some react projects.
So this is the most popular use cases, what you can do with it, hop a pilot, I hope it was
really useful to you and stay with me, stay with next lessons, where I do explain to you
how to use it, so see you in the next lessons.